Earth.
土强
本作品采用知识共享CC BY-NC-SA共享 3.0 中国大陆许可协议进行许可
本字幕仅仅供爱好者学习交流，请勿用作商业用途！
Fire.
火烈
Air.
气和
Water.
水善
Only the Avatar can master all four elements
只有神通能掌握所有四种元素
and bring balance to the world.
并为世界带来平衡
降世神通：科拉传奇
After fusing with Vaatu, Unalaq became a dark Avatar
融合了瓦图之后，吴纳克变成了暗黑逆神通
and ripped Korra and Raava apart.
并且分离了科拉和拉瓦
By destroying Raava,
摧毁拉瓦后
Unalaq and Vaatu transformed into the most powerful dark spirit that's ever lived.
吴纳克和瓦图变成了有史以来最强大的黑暗神灵
Tenzin managed to free Jinora from the fog of lost souls,
丹增设法从迷魂雾中将吉诺拉解救出来
but her spiritual quest isn't over yet.
但是她的灵界之旅还没有结束
Can anyone save the world from eternal darkness?
有谁能从永恒的黑暗中拯救这个世界吗？
第十四集：暗中之光
第二册：神灵篇
Pretty.
真漂亮
General Iroh, are your ships in position?
艾洛将军，你的舰队就位了吗？
Yes, Mr. president, but I need to know what kind of enemy we're dealing with.
是的，总统先生
但是我得知道，我们要对付的是什么样的敌人
It's time to take back the physical world.
是时候夺回物质世界了
Fire!
开火！
Monster attack!
怪物发动攻击了
They're over here!
他们在这边
Please, wake up.
拜托，快醒醒
They're going to be all right,
他们会没事的
but I need to get them into some spirit water right away.
但是我得马上把他们放到灵水里面去
Thank goodness you're all okay.
谢天谢地，你们都没事
Did you find Jinora?
你找到吉诺拉了没有？
I was able to rescue her soul,
我本可以救出她的魂魄
but she wasn't ready to return to her body yet.
但是她还没打算回到她的身体里面
She sense the world was in grave danger.
她感觉世界正在极度危险之中
She was right.
她是对的
Were you able to stop Unalaq and Vaatu?
你阻止吴纳克和瓦图了吗？
No, they fused,
不，他们融合了
then Vaatu ripped Raava right out of me and destroyed her.
然后瓦图把拉瓦从我身体里拉了出来并且摧毁了她
Vaatu won.
瓦图赢了
No! I'm too young
不！我的寿命短暂
to live through 10,000 years of darkness.
可没法在黑暗的岁月中活一万年
Korra, can't you talk to one of your past lives or something?
科拉，你现在不能去和前世对话之类的吗？
When Vaatu destroyed Raava,
当瓦图摧毁了拉瓦时
he destroyed my connection to the past Avatars too.
他也切断了我和前世神通们的联系
If that's true, then...
如果那是真的，那么
the cycle is over.
轮回终结了
I'm the last Avatar.
我就是最后的降世神通了
I'm so sorry, Tenzin.
我真的很抱歉，丹增
She needs you now, more than ever.
她现在比任何时候都更需要你
It's going to destroy the entire city.
他要摧毁整座城市
We're going down.
我们在坠落
It's pandemonium in the streets.
街上真是一团乱啊
Giant vines are destroying everything.
巨藤正在摧毁一切
This is Shiro Shinobi signing off...
这里是忍四郎，现场为您报道
Zhu Li, commence operation "winged freedom!"
朱莉，开始执行“自由之翼”
Do the thing!
打开机器！
The other Avatars may not be able to help you anymore,
其他的神通恐怕是帮不上你什么忙了
but perhaps I can.
但是或许我能
No one can help me now.
现在谁也帮不了我了
I know I haven't been the best mentor to you,
我知道，我可能算不上是你最好的导师
but I realized it was because I had a lot of spiritual growth to do myself.
但是我认识到这是因为我自己在精神上也有很多需要成长的地方
There may still be a way for you to stop Vaatu.
你也许还有个办法可以阻止瓦图
How?
什么办法？
Let go of your attachment to who you <i>think</i> you are,
放开你对自我身份的执着
and connect with your inner spirit.
并且和你本来的自我灵魂相连
Haven't you heard anything I said?
你没把我说的话听进去吗？
Raava is gone.
拉瓦已经不在了
I'm not connected to a spirit anymore.
我再也无法和神灵相连接了
I'm not talking about Raava.
我不是在说拉瓦
Raava is not who you are.
拉瓦并不是真正的你
Come with me.
跟我来
I need to show you something.
我要让你看一些东西
Why are you showing me Vaatu's prison?
为什么你要给我看瓦图的监牢？
Because this tree had a history long before it held Vaatu.
因为这棵树的历史在囚禁瓦图之前就早有了
This is the tree of time.
这是时间之树
And the legends say that its roots bind the spirit and physical worlds together.
传说它的根把灵界和人界连接在一起
And you think this tree can help me somehow?
你觉得这棵树还能帮得上我？
Yes, I have read that long ago,
对，我很久以前就从书上了解到
the ancients would meditate beneath this tree
古人们在这棵树中冥思
and connect with the great cosmic energy of the universe.
与宇宙的无限能量相连接
These are my memories.
这都是我的记忆
The tree of time remembers all.
时间之树能记得一切
Korra, the most powerful thing about you is not the spirit of Raava,
科拉，你最强大之处并不是拉瓦神灵
but your own inner spirit.
而是你自己内心深处的灵魂
You have always been strong, unyielding, and fearless.
你始终都强大，无畏，不屈不挠
Avatar Wan.
神通万
Before he fused with Raava,
在他和拉瓦融合之前
Wan was just a regular person.
他只是个平常人
But he was brave and smart
但是他又勇敢又聪明
and always wanted to defend the helpless.
总是乐于保护弱小
That's right.
这就对了
He became a legend because of who he was,
他之所以成为传奇是因为他是谁
not what he was.
而不是他是什么
He wasn't defined by Raava any more than you are.
他的自我并没有比你更多地由拉瓦来定义
Everyone in Republic City is in danger.
共和城内的所有人都在危险之中
You have to help them, Korra.
你必须拯救他们，科拉
How?
怎么做？
They're halfway around the world.
他们离我们有半个世界远
Do as the ancients once did.
就像古人曾经做过的那样
Connect to the cosmic energy of the universe.
和宇宙的能量相连接
Don't bend the elements, but the energy within yourself.
不是控制元素，而是去控制你内在的能量
You really think I can do this?
你真的认为我能做到？
I have no doubt.
我毫不怀疑
Thank you for not giving up on me.
谢谢你没有放弃我
I'm proud of you.
我真为你骄傲
If you and Vaatu have the same fight every 10,000 years,
既然你和瓦图每一万年就要战斗一次
why hasn't one of you destroyed the other?
为什么你们中没有任何一个被摧毁？
He cannot destroy light any more than I can destroy darkness.
黑暗是无法战胜光明的，同理光明也无法消灭黑暗
One cannot exist without the other.
我们两个是互相依存的
Find the light in the dark.
找到暗中之光
Uh... What did you say to her, exactly?
你跟她到底说了什么
Korra's back.
科拉回来了
And she's a blue giant.
而且她成了个蓝色巨人
You are looking for something that is gone.
你要寻找的东西已经不复存在
Raava has been destroyed.
拉瓦已经被我杀死了
And soon you will be too!
马上就轮到你了
They're coming for Korra.
他们来抓科拉了
Leave my Bolin alone!
离我的波林远点
I am so done with spirits.
我已经受够神灵了
Eska! I love you!
爱丝卡，我爱你！
Let's face the end of the world together!
让我们一起来面对世界末日吧
You're so romantic.
你还真是浪漫
With you out of the way,
只要消灭了你
I will be the one true Avatar.
我就能成为唯一真正的神通
Mommy, it's Jinora.
妈妈，是吉诺拉
She's... Beautiful.
她……好美
What? Let me see.
什么？让我看看
Be careful, sweetie!
小心点，甜心！
吉诺拉手上的是光明灵蝶，别忘了上集结尾哦……
No!
不！
拉瓦与光明灵蝶产生共鸣，在瓦图体内的具体位置暴露出来
Raava.
拉瓦
Go in peace.
平静下来吧
Harmonic convergence is nearly over.
谐波汇聚快要结束了
We must return to the spirit world so we can fuse once again.
我们必须回到灵界，好再次融合
I'll see you soon, dad.
一会儿见，爸爸
Gran-gran, I missed you.
奶奶，我好想你
What about Korra and the others?
科拉和其他人呢
Don't worry. They're all right.
别担心
Korra saved the world.
科拉拯救了世界
Her Avatar spirit has returned.
她的神通之魂也回来了
It's over.
结束了
I don't even know what to say.
我都不知道该怎么说才好
You were amazing.
你简直太厉害了
And the way you turned all gigantic like that, wow!
还有你变成巨人的那种场景
I just wish Varrick had been here to film it.
我真希望瓦里克能在现场把它录下来
It would have been the greatest mover ever.
那将是有史以来最棒的电影
After <i>the Nuktuk chronicles,</i> of course.
当然，在《纳塔克历险记》之后
I'm sorry about your father,
你们父亲的事我很抱歉
but he was already fused with Vaatu.
但他已经和瓦图合体
I couldn't save him.
我无法挽救他
It seems cousin Korra is under the impression
看起来科拉是怕我们
we are saddened by our father's demise.
受到父亲之死的打击
But I will not miss him at all.
不过事实上我一点都不想念他
In the end, he became a deplorable man.
到最后，他已经让我们愤恨不已
Agreed.
我同意
But how will we explain this to mother?
但是我们该怎么向母亲解释呢？
So I was thinking, I'm not really a fan of the long-distance relationship thing.
我想，我可接受不了异地恋
So how about you move to Republic City with me?
所以，你搬到共和城来如何？
I do not think that will be possible.
我认为这不可能
Okay, Desna can come too.
好吧，杰斯纳也可以来
I will not be joining you, Bolin.
我不能跟着你了，波林
Desna and I must return home.
杰斯纳和我必须回家
But you said...
但你说过
Eternal darkness was upon us.
当时在我们面前的是永恒的黑暗
I became caught up in the moment.
那一刻我有点迷糊了
Yeah.
是啊
I guess I did too.
我想我也是
But... You will always hold a special place in the organ that pumps my blood.
不过，你在我的心中，会一直占据特殊的位置
I will remember you fondly, my turtle-duck.
我会深情地想念着你，我的小龟鸭
Bum-Ju, you're okay.
小布，你还好吧
I missed you, little buddy.
小伙计，我好想你
Now that you're bonded with Raava once again,
既然你又一次跟拉瓦合体了
are you also reconnected to your past lives?
那么你还能联系到你的前世们吗
No.
不能
I think that link is gone forever.
我认为和他们的联系已经永远断掉了
I see.
我明白了
Why don't you close the portals and we'll go home.
你为什么不关掉通道，然后我们回家
Maybe I shouldn't.
也许我不该这么做
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
What if Unalaq was right when he said the Avatar shouldn't be a bridge between the two worlds?
如果吴纳克没错，如他所说神通不该是两个世界的桥梁？
What if Avatar Wan made a mistake when he closed the portals?
如果神通万关闭通道的确是一个错误？
What if humans and spirits weren't meant to live apart?
如果人类和神灵本不应该分居两界？
Well, what do you think I should do?
那么，你认为我应该怎么做
I think you should trust your instincts.
我认为你应该相信你的直觉
There is nothing else I can teach you.
这里已经没有什么是我可以教给你的
You are the Avatar.
你是降世神通
Whatever your decision, I support you.
无论你做出什么决定，我都会支持你
Hey, can we talk?
嗨，我们能聊聊吗？
Of course.
当然可以
There's something I've been wanting to tell you about that fight we had.
有点事情我一直想告诉你，关于我们的吵架
I know I said it wasn't that bad,
我知道我说过那没有那么严重
but that's not exactly true.
但是那不是真相
I, um... I broke up with you.
我，呃…我和你分手了
I remember.
我知道
But I thought you said you lost part of your memory?
可是，我以为你说你丧失了部分记忆？
I did, but being inside the tree of time brought it back.
的确是这样，但在时间之树里，我找回了记忆
I'm sorry for blowing up at you.
我很抱歉我对你发了火
That's okay.
没有关系
I think we both said some things that we regret.
我觉得我们都说了让我们后悔的话
Why didn't you just tell me the truth in the first place?
为什么当初你不告诉我真相？
I know I should have, but
我知道我本该这么做
I didn't wanna hurt you all over again.
但是我不想再次伤害你
I guess part of me wanted to forget about the breakup too.
我想我的部分内心也想让我忘记这次分手
I think we both know that this...
我认为我们都知道这个
Us...
我们的关系
Doesn't work.
行不通的
You're right.
你说的对
It's over.
已经结束了
For real this time.
这次真的结束了
I'll always love you, Korra.
我一直都很爱你，科拉
And I'll always love you.
我也一直爱你
You want a hug?
你想要一个拥抱吗？
The war of the water tribes is over.
水族内战结束了
Unalaq has been defeated
吴纳克被击败
and the northern fleet is returning home.
而且北方水族舰队正在返回家乡
The water tribes will always be allies,
南北水族部落将永远是盟友
but the Southern tribe is now independent.
但是现在南极水族部落已经独立
And the Southern council of elders
而南水族的长老议会
has appointed my father, Tonraq,
任命我的父亲，托纳克
to be your new chief.
成为你们新的族长
I've realized that even though we should learn from those who came before us,
我知道，虽然我们应该从前人身上学习
we must also forge our own path.
但我们也必须修筑我们自己前进的道路
So that is why I've decided to keep the portals open.
这就是我为什么决定要保持通道开放
Humans can now physically enter the spirit world
人类现在可以亲身进入灵界
and spirits will be free to roam our world.
而神灵也会自在地在我们的世界畅游
I will no longer be the bridge.
我将不再是两界的桥梁
Humans and spirits must learn to live together.
人类和神灵必须学会一同生活
My mission will always be to use Raava's light spirit
我的使命将永远是运用拉瓦的光明的灵力
to guide the world toward peace and balance.
去引导世界走向和平与平衡
Harmonic convergence has caused a shift in the planet's energy.
谐波汇聚使得这个星球的能量发生了变化
I can feel it.
我能感受到它
Things will never be the same again.
事物将与曾经再不相同
We are entering a new age.
我们正在进入一个新的时代
降世神通贴吧&Brony United
片源：Ult-Kimi 翻译：NightScream，蓝色的夏天，风起裘庄
校对：Ult-Kimi，水族神通 调轴：水族神通
本作品采用知识共享CC BY-NC-SA共享 3.0 中国大陆许可协议进行许可
本字幕仅仅供爱好者学习交流，请勿用作商业用途！
第三册：易篇
(Change)
放送决定